mysteryscience.com 2019-04-06

# Privacy - Mystery Science

## Effective: November 15, 2018

This Privacy Policy explains how information is collected, used and disclosed by Mystery Science, Inc. with respect to your access and use of our services. This Privacy Policy doesn’t apply to any websites, services or applications operated or provided by other companies that can be accessed through our services.

Any information that is collected is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected. We may, however, modify and revise our Privacy Policy from time-to-time. If we make any material changes to this policy, we will notify you of those changes by posting them on our website, through our services or by sending you an email or other notification, and we will indicate when those changes will become effective. By continuing to access or use our services after those changes become effective, you are agreeing to be bound by the revised policy.

**Information You Provide**

**Account Registration Information.** We will collect personal information from you (like your name and email address) when you register for an account. If you create an account using your login from another online account (like Facebook), we will access and collect the information about you that you choose to share (which is based on the permissions you give) when you create your account with us.

**Referrals.** Our website offers a tool that allow you to refer colleagues and other contacts to use our website and services by providing their email addresses. We will use the email addresses you provide to send an email inviting the recipient to use our services. This email will come from you to the recipient and the contents of the email will be what you write. If the recipient does not respond to the invitation, we may send a single reminder email from Mystery Science. We may also share anonymous information you provide with our advertising partners to improve the targeting of online advertisements for our services.

**Membership Purchases.** When you purchase a Mystery Science membership, we may collect information necessary to process your transaction, including your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, payment information, such as a credit card number and/or other related information that may be required from you to complete your purchase ("Financial Information"). Unless we tell you otherwise at the time of your purchase we do not collect, store or maintain your Financial Information. For more information on how your information is shared in these instances, please see the Section "Third-Party Payment Processing" below.

**Communications with Us.** We may collect information from you such as email address, phone number or mailing address when you contact us to request information about our services, register for a newsletter or a loyalty program that we may offer from time to time, request to receive customer or technical support or otherwise communicate with us.

**Featured Questions.** From time to time, we may want to feature questions and comments from users and students on our website. When a teacher submits a featured question, the teacher includes the first name and grade of the student. Before featuring a student in a video on our website, we will send the teacher a permission form to obtain parental consent for the student to participate in the recording of a video. Participation in this recorded video is optional and will never proceed without a signed parental consent form.

Note regarding children: We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under 13, we will take steps to delete such information from our files as soon as possible.

Note regarding international users: Information that is provided to us will be transferred to and maintained on computers located in the United States (or any other country where we operate) and processed there – by providing us with your information, you are acknowledging and agreeing to that transfer.

**Information We Collect**

We collect certain information that your web browser sends when you visit our website, like the Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser, pages viewed, and other such information about your use of our services. We use "cookies" – small data files that are installed on your Internet browser – to collect this information, which allows us to identify your browser and to improve your use of our services, for example, by speeding your login experience. You can set your web browser to refuse these cookies, however, some features of our services may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

**Information Collected by Others**

We may enable other companies to collect usage analytics about our services. These companies may place their own cookies on your device to collect traffic and activity data in order to deliver us relevant metrics and information. We may also share anonymous or aggregated information about our users with them to help improve our services. We will also share data with ad networks like Facebook, Google, Pinterest and similar ad service providers to measure the effectiveness of our ad campaigns. We may also use Google’s & Facebook’s remarketing services to advertise our services to previous visitors to our site when they visit other websites and social networks. Google & Facebook use cookies or pixels to serve ads on other sites based on visits to our website. The collection of this data by these companies is subject to their own privacy policy. For more information visit: [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/), [Facebook's Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation), [Pinterest’s Privacy Policy](https://policy.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy).

You can opt out of remarketing and otherwise configure your ad settings by visiting:

You can control your Google ad preferences here: <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en>

You can control your Facebook ad preferences here: <https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/edit/>

You may also visit the Digital Advertising Alliance’s WebChoices tool to opt-out of interest based advertising on your browser at [http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/).

Additionally, if you would like to opt out of Google’s collection of data through Google Analytics, <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**How We Use the Information We Collect**

We use the information we collect to provide our services (or the information you request), to process and complete any transactions, to respond to inquiries, to personalize and improve our services and your experiences when you use our services, to monitor and analyze usage and trends of our services, to send you messages regarding the operation and use of our services, and for any other purpose for which the information was collected.

**Information We Share With Others**

We will share information about you when you instruct us to do so, such as if we notify you that the information you provide will be shared in a particular manner and you provide such information.

We will share information about you if we are (or if we believe we are) required by law or legal process (such as a subpoena, warrant or court order), if we have to respond to a lawful request from legal authorities to disclose such information, or if we need to enforce or apply this Privacy Policy or our other terms and policies.

Your information may be accessed and used by our service providers who are working with us in connection with the operation of our services. These service providers may have access to your information but only to the extent necessary to perform services on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose that information or use it for any other purposes.

We may share information about you in anonymous and/or aggregated form (that doesn’t identify someone individually) with other companies for usage analytics (to help us better understand who is using our services and how), to improve the relevancy of the content you see on our services (to tailor it to your interests) and for industry analysis, demographic profiling, research, and other similar purposes. We may also transfer and/or provide information about our users in connection with an acquisition, sale of company assets, or other situation where user information would be transferred as one of our business assets.

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, financing due diligence, reorganization, bankruptcy, receivership, sale of company assets or transition of service to another provider, then your information may be sold or transferred as part of such a transaction as permitted by law and/or contract.

**Third Party Payment Information**

When you make purchases through the services, we process your payments through a Third-Party payment service provider. In these instances the Third-Party payment service may collect certain Financial Information from you to process a payment on behalf of us, including your name, email address, address and other billing information in which case the use and storage of your Financial Information is governed by the Third-Party payment service provider’s terms, conditions and privacy policies. Our treatment of any Financial Information that we may process on your behalf, or that we receive from our financing partners, is subject to this Privacy Policy.

**Opting Out of Marketing Communications**

If you receive an unwanted email from us, you can use the unsubscribe link found at the bottom of the email to opt-out of receiving future emails. We will process your request within a reasonable time after receipt. Note that you will continue to receive transaction-related emails regarding products or services you have requested. We may also send you certain non-promotional communications regarding the services, and you will not be able to opt-out of those communications (e.g., communications regarding updates to our Terms or this Privacy Policy).

**How to Access Your Information**

You can access and modify the information you provided us through your account settings. If you completely delete all such information, then your account will become deactivated and you will no longer be able to access our services through your account. If you would like us to delete personal information about you from our system, please contact us with a request that we delete your personal information from our database. We will use reasonable efforts to honor your request; however, we may retain an archived copy of your information as required by law and/or for record keeping purposes.

**Security Measures We Take To Protect Your Information**

We employ administrative, physical and electronic measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access, however, despite these efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable and no method of data transmission can be guaranteed against any interception or other type of misuse. In the event that your personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of our security measures, we will promptly notify you if your personal information has been compromised, as required by applicable law.

**"Do Not Track"**

Do Not Track ("DNT") is a privacy preference that users can set in certain web browsers. DNT is a way for users to inform websites and services that they do not want certain information about their webpage visits collected over time and across websites or online services. Please note that we do not respond to or honor DNT signals or similar mechanisms transmitted by web browsers. 

**Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact us.
